MAUREEN DIDIER, SCHOOL OF SOCIAL WELFARE 25TH ANNIVERSARY ORAL HISTORY COLLECTION (UA902.019) 1990-1991
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Maureen Didier, School of Social Welfare 25th Anniversary Oral History Collection1990-1991
nam_ua902.019
0.33
State University of New York at Albany. School of Social Welfare
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Maureen Didier, School of Social Welfare 25th Anniversary Oral History Collection contains interviews with students, graduates, faculty, administrators and other personnel of the School of Social Welfare at the University at Albany.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Maureen Didier donated this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
The School of Social Welfare at the University at Albany was founded in December 1963. Dr. Richardson L. Rice served as the school's first dean and, in 1964, began efforts to establish a two-year master's program in social welfare. The first class of twenty-seven students entered the master's program in the fall of 1965 and graduated on June 11, 1967.
Dr. Maureen Didier joined the faculty of the School of Social Welfare in August 1967 as associate professor directly after receiving her doctorate in social work from the Smith College School for Social Work. Didier later served as associate dean beginning in 1972.
In honor of the School of Social Welfare's 25th anniversary, Didier and the Rev. Clinton Dugger, a 1967 graduate, served as co-chairs of a yearlong silver anniversary celebration. The oral history project, conducted 25 years after the first class of students entered the master's degree program, was one part of that celebration. Other activities included a Convocation, exhibits in the Dewey Library, creation of a special anniversary song, alumni dinners, and a lecture sponsored by the Ringel Institute.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains video and audio cassette interviews of students, graduates, faculty, administrators and other personnel documenting the history of the School of Social Welfare on the occasion of its 25th anniversary. Professor Maureen Didier conducted all the interviews with the exception of one 1991 video taped interview with current students, conducted by Mary McCarthy.
For more information about the School of Social Welfare, its students, faculty and administration, please see the School of Social Welfare Records (UA-690) and the Ringel Institute for Gerontology Records (UA–690.015). For specific information on the School's 25th anniversary, see the School of Social Welfare Records, Series 5, box 1, folders 16-17.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Interviews with Students and Graduates, 1991
Series 2 - Interviews with Deans of the School of Social Welfare, 1990-1991
Series 3 - Interviews with Faculty, Administrators and Other Personnel, 1990-1991
The collection contains three series. Series 1 collection is arranged chronologically. Series 2 is arranged chronologically by date of deanship. Series 3 is arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewee.
Subject and Genre Headings
State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany. School of Social Welfare; Oral history--New York (State); Schools of social work--New York (State)--Albany--Faculty; Schools of social work--New York (State)--Albany--Students; Higher Education--New York (State); Audiocassettes; VHS (TM); Videocassettes
Container List
- Interviews with Graduates and Students, 1991; 1; 0.03
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains videotaped interviews conducted by Maureen Didier with graduates from the Master's of Social Welfare (MSW) classes of 1967 and 1977. Mary McCarthy also conducted interviews with current students in the master's program in 1991. According to the School of Social Welfare Records, attendees of the School's 25th anniversary Convocation on April 11, 1991 informally viewed these interviews during the reception portion of the event.
  - Maureen Didier interviews with students from 1st MSW Class of 1967, 1991 February 27; 42 minutes (Video-tape 1)
  - Maureen Didier interviews with students from MSW Classes of 1977 and 1978, 1991 March 01; 42 minutes (Video-tape 2)
  - Mary McCarthy interviews with students from the MSW Class of 1991, 1991 March 01 (Video-tape 3)
- Interviews with Deans of the School of Social Welfare, 1990-1991; 2; 0.15
  Arranged chronologically by date of deanship.
  This series contains audio cassette interviews conducted by Maureen Didier with Deans of the School of Social Welfare.
  - Maureen Didier interview with Mrs. Richardson Rice, 1991 April 13; Wife of the first dean of the School of Social Welfare, Richardson L. Rice, 1964-1969 (Cassette 1)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Charles O’Reilly, 1990 June 07; Ph.D., Dean, 1969-1970, 1971-1976 (Cassette 2-3)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Stuart Kirk, 1991 November 16; DSW, Dean, 1980-1989 (Cassette 4-5)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Susan Sherman, 1991 October 18; Ph.D., Professor SSW, Acting Dean, 1989-1990 (Cassette 6)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Lynn Videka-Sherman, 1990 October 18; 1990 October 24; Ph.D., Dean, 1990-2000 (Cassette 7)
- Interviews with Faculty, Administrators and Other Personnel, 1990-1991; 3; 0.15
  Arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewees.
  This series contains audio cassette interviews conducted by Maureen Didier with faculty, administrators, graduates, a librarian and interested parties of the School of Social Welfare.
  - Maureen Didier interview with Cecile B. David, 1990 November 09; Assistant Dean for Field Instruction, 1967-1984 (Cassette 1)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Edgar Flinton, 1990 November 16; Ed.D., Dean Emeritus of Graduate Studies, SUNYA, 1952-1971 (Cassette 2)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Elizabeth Wolff Heinmiller, 1991 October 10; NENY NASW Chapter Chair and Chair, Committee on Development of Graduate School of Social Work, 1962-1963 (Cassette 3)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Professor Emeritus Jane K. Ives, 1990 June 28; Re. the preparation and early period of the SSW (Cassette 4-5)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Mrs. Mary Koechley, 1991 June 11; Re. area training needs, the development of the continuing education program for NYS workers, and professional practice in Albany County, NY, 1938-1944 (Cassette 6-7)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Anna May Lilly, 1990 July 06; Organizer of School of Social Welfare Library, Director, 1967-1971 (Cassette 8)
  - Maureen Didier interview with William S. Rooney, 1990 October 20; DSW, Professor Emeritus of SSW, Acting Dean, 1970-1971 (Cassette 9)
  - Maureen Didier interview with Min Wachs, 1990 June 28; Secretary at SSW during preparation of school and early years of graduate program (Cassette 10)